[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957c", "question": "What won an Emmy for outstanding music direction in 1985?", "answer": "Christmas In Washington", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a552ee3e1c6f9840ba319e", "question": "On the 1976 release, who wanted to \"Fly Like an Eagle\"?", "answer": "Steve Miller Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febaf0d7e83c707845b20fa", "question": "What is the most venomous fish in the world?", "answer": "Reef stonefish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062b9fc9d816e292245c21", "question": "Who is credited with writing \"The Odyssey\" and \"The Iliad\"?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e6", "question": "What name is given to the ancient Christian and Jewish underground burial chambers in and around Rome?", "answer": "Catacombs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc776ec223966ae8f888d", "question": "In TV, what is Leonard Hofstader's middle name?", "answer": "Leakey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a767", "question": "In which US state is Gettysburg National Military Park?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5ef46ce05a3942286e3c", "question": "Who had a hit song with the theme from the movie \"Ghostbusters\"?", "answer": "Ray Parker, Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e38ce17f6c8a670a7957c52", "question": "What is Jean Valjean's prison number in the novel \"Les Miserables\"?", "answer": "24601", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c2", "question": "What is Albumen the correct term for?", "answer": "Egg White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c90d01152800b05cac20f0c", "question": "In what city was Bruce Lee born in?", "answer": "San Francisco, California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391db", "question": "Who played the godfather in the movie \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c594", "question": "What is the alligator pear better known as?", "answer": "An avocado", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bad6", "question": "In 1996, what became the first minivan to be named Motor Trend magazine's \"Car of the Year\"?", "answer": "Dodge Caravan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c0", "question": "What singer was declared dead on New Years' Day in 1953 at the age of 29?\u00a0", "answer": "Hank Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a51a", "question": "The Banff Airport is located in which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b740", "question": "Who is widely credited as being the inventor of the modern commercially available toilet paper?", "answer": "Joseph Gayetty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba6", "question": "What famous baseball poem was written by Ernest Lawrence Thayer?", "answer": "Casey at the Bat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf3", "question": "In what city did the Hindenburg airship disaster occur?", "answer": "Lakehurst, New Jersey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab7", "question": "On Mount Rushmore, which one of the presidents is wearing a jacket?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57a", "question": "Coney Island is located on what island?", "answer": "Long Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfeb", "question": "What type of foodstuff is traditionally eaten on Shrove Tuesday?", "answer": "Pancakes\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c214", "question": "Which country were the 1932 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United States", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b77c", "question": "According to legend, the \"Witch of November\" had a hand in the fate of what ship?", "answer": "Edmund Fitzgerald", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d2", "question": "What did Harry Houdini die from on Halloween in 1926?", "answer": "Ruptured appendix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec23ce8dc25ca9e12ef633", "question": "What don't the children need in Pink Floyd's \"Another Brick In The Wall\"?", "answer": "An education", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf87", "question": "Which male vocal range is pitched between tenor and bass?", "answer": "Baritone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c5c50775fa611bce67cb", "question": "Turmeric is a popular spice that is used in Asian dishes.  What other use does it have?", "answer": "Turmeric is also a powerful anti-inflammatory often used in traditional medicine.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0b", "question": "What US state is the Catalina Island located in?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e38cf45f6c8a670a7957c54", "question": "Including the end zones, how many yards long is the standard American football field?", "answer": "120 yards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a6dd20565ad31a57c7e0", "question": "Who was the founding commandant of the Nazi concentration camp Auschwitz?", "answer": "Rudolph H\u00f6ss", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c48a", "question": "What color are cranberries before they turn red?", "answer": "White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba59", "question": "What type of pasta\u2019s name mean \u201clittle tongues\u201d in Italian?", "answer": "Linguini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd93", "question": "Who merged with the struggling Cleveland Barons in 1978?", "answer": "The Minnesota North Stars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede4226ce05a3942286dd8", "question": "What was the name of the 1976 Led Zeppelin concert film?", "answer": "The Song Remains the Same", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfdffe3b668d7dfe168b5bd", "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a18", "question": "What Italian town takes tourists to the workshop of renowned stringent-instrument maker Antonio Stradivari?", "answer": "Cremona", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aef", "question": "What is a \"dhampir\"?", "answer": "A half human, half vampire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339771", "question": "Which actor plays Tony Montana in Scarface?", "answer": "Al Pacino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f96", "question": "What two words were tattooed on Robert Mitchum's knuckles in \"The Night of the Hunter\"?", "answer": "Love and Hate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb11", "question": "What early arcade game used a trackball rather than a joystick?", "answer": "Missile Command", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3b", "question": "What are the three yellow properties on the standards Monopoly board?", "answer": "Marvin Gardens, Atlantic Avenue and Ventnor Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f8b001dd7bf43be5e846", "question": "\"All the news that's fit to print\" is the motto of which newspaper?", "answer": "The New York Times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bafd", "question": "In what year was Howard Hughes born?", "answer": "1905", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8a", "question": "What did the 13th Constitutional Amendment ban?", "answer": "Slavery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c025", "question": "What is ochophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Riding in vehicles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339919", "question": "What was John Ritter\u2019s character\u2019s name in the TV show \"Three\u2019s Company\"?", "answer": "Jack Tripper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7abd196490a8cc1a6e529d", "question": "In The Maze Runner, the \"killzone\" refers to what?", "answer": "The Brain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ec", "question": "What is a newly hatched fish called?", "answer": "\"Fry\"", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca68", "question": "What kind of birds would you find in a gaggle?", "answer": "Geese", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea2", "question": "Who was the first man to swim the English channel?", "answer": "Captain Mathew Webb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923f", "question": "What movie star had hit records singing with Ewan McGregor and Robbie Williams?", "answer": "Nicole Kidman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40f", "question": "What year did Bangladesh declare its independence from Pakistan?", "answer": "1971", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133990b", "question": "What TV show character lived at 129 West 81st St, Apt. 5A in New York City?", "answer": "Jerry Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc12d0469bb8041d07a07d", "question": "What direction should you stir your Christmas pudding according to tradition?", "answer": "East to West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ea", "question": "Which is the second largest US state in surface area?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b530", "question": "What color is bianco wine?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c104", "question": "Carbonade Flamande is a dish made with what beverage?", "answer": "Beer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c32", "question": "How many seasons did the TV show \"Twin Peaks\" run for?", "answer": "2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede1cb6ce05a3942286dc5", "question": "In a Thanksgiving episode on TV's \"Friends\", what dish did Monica have to make for Ross?", "answer": "Lumpy mashed potatoes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d4", "question": "What is Billie Holiday's birth name?", "answer": "Eleanora Fagan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133add7", "question": "When did the \"Eighty Years War\" start?", "answer": "1568", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b026", "question": "What Native American leader surrendered at Skeleton Canyon in 1886?", "answer": "Geronimo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5e", "question": "What artist, who died in 1986, was famous for her Southwestern paintings?", "answer": "Georgia O\u2019Keefe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe12d0de39efa6330e0fec9", "question": "How long is the Panama Canal?", "answer": "51 miles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b60", "question": "What 1970's TV series was revived in 2007 with Michelle Ryan in the title role?", "answer": "Bionic Woman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c56", "question": "What was the name of Whitney Houston's 1985 debut album?", "answer": "Whitney Houston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa55c73838c5c8a417f24", "question": "Which creatures produce gossamer?", "answer": "Spiders", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ccf7851b37b32637bdc44b9", "question": "Who has won the most NFL MVP awards (as of 2019)?", "answer": "Peyton Manning (5)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c005", "question": "What is the study of stamps called?", "answer": "Philately", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a3f312f2a7826b9b872b", "question": "What do the letters in UNESCO's name stand for?", "answer": "United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d4", "question": "In what year were Skittles candy first sold in the US?", "answer": "1974", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bb357612627b8fe95581be3", "question": "What is the capital of the Australian state, Queensland?", "answer": "Brisbane", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339423", "question": "What basketball player starred alongside Jean Claude Van Damme in the movie \"Double Team\"?", "answer": "Dennis Rodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c407", "question": "Who is typically credited with inventing the first DC motor in 1837?", "answer": "Thomas Davenport", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd0", "question": "In what city was the Wright brothers' bicycle shop?", "answer": "Dayton, Ohio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600244b84be4723ccac221a7", "question": "What artist drew the comic strip Bloom County from 1980 to 1989?", "answer": "\"Bloom County\"\u00a0is a comic strip by\u00a0Berkeley Breathed\u00a0which examines events in politics and culture in small-town Middle America.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049a0bcf93664eb1048697", "question": "The Queensland nut is another name for what nut?", "answer": "Macadamia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3f", "question": "What duo composed the operetta \"Porgy and Bess\"?", "answer": "George Gershwin and Ira Gershwin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ffaa83a3a814d89068c5d", "question": "In the 1988 film \"Twins\", what were the character names of Arnold Schwarzenneger and Danny De Vito?", "answer": "Julius and Vincent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3236a0bf195a31e15d73bd", "question": "What geologic period is also known as the \"Age of Fish\"?", "answer": "Devonian period", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c9", "question": "What folk singer was born Robert Zimmerman?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e2", "question": "Who was William Claude Dukenfield better known as?", "answer": "W. C. Fields", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9cd", "question": "In which continent would you find the Mackenzie river?\u00a0", "answer": "North America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062d9ac9d816e292245c34", "question": "Who painted \"The Scream\"?", "answer": "Edvard Munch\u00a0painted \"The Scream.\"  His style is recognized by most critics as leading to the birth of German Expressionism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab979f86faa38a764be52a", "question": "What is the Wankel engine typically referred to as?", "answer": "Rotary engine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cca0877e98cb97778a28", "question": "What country would you have to visit to enjoy a taste of Hymettus honey?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59bb2853c9bff04efae6d74f", "question": "The song \"Son of My Father\" is credited as being the first number 1 UK hit to feature which instument?", "answer": "A synthesizer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afde", "question": "The gun battle at the O.K. Corral was fought between the Earp Brothers and what gang?", "answer": "Clanton Gang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7abce66490a8cc1a6e529c", "question": "In The Maze Runner, what does \"WICKED\" stand for?", "answer": "World In Catastrophe: Killzone Experiment Department", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a540", "question": "Lopez Island, Orcas Island and Waldron Island all belong to what archipelago?", "answer": "San Juan Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab8c", "question": "Which Gulf is located southwest of Cambodia?", "answer": "Gulf of Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febd4907e83c707845b215e", "question": "Which show holds the record for being the longest-running American science-fiction television program?", "answer": "\"Stargate SG-1\" ran for 10 years (1997-2007) and ended at a record (for American science fiction) 214 episodes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec26ac8dc25ca9e12ef64e", "question": "What is a male goose called?", "answer": "Gander", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a004", "question": "What British TV series featured Jeff Tracy and Lady Penelope Creighton-Ward?", "answer": "Thunderbirds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60160078fe83fe1f2a824c54", "question": "May Day festivities are traditionally linked to the celebration of what?", "answer": "Being a holiday set in the season of Spring, the pagan societies which created May Day, used it celebrate fertility.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c98f0775fa611bce67ec", "question": "What is the decorative strip along the top of a wall called?", "answer": "Molding -- It comes from Classical architecture, where they were designed to give a building character and hide its imperfections.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a87", "question": "In \"Minority Report\", what part of Tom Cruise's anatomy does his character replace to help him avoid authorities?", "answer": "His eyes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5954e9c08e82ccaf3b9a67bc", "question": "What food group is a cucumber technically in?", "answer": "Fruits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee5", "question": "What future \"Grey's Anatomy\" costar played Sandra Oh's lover in the movie \"Under the Tuscan Sun\"?", "answer": "Kate Walsh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fcd8a4edfd43a087adc2", "question": "What number is represented by \"I\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "1", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5efa94e7ccb363a2cbc5227b", "question": "What Spanish word refers to a deep gully and precedes \"Grande\" in the name of a village in Southern California?", "answer": "Arroyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5feddf2f6ce05a3942286daf", "question": "Which NBA player once costarred alongside Jean-Claude Van Damme in a major Hollywood action movie?", "answer": "Dennis Rodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ab9226490a8cc1a6e528f", "question": "Who was the protagonist in the book \"Fahrenheit 451\"?", "answer": "Guy Montag", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8af5ec223966ae8f8835", "question": "In what book of the Bible did the prison warden find Andy's rock hammer in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Exodus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7ecafb24f84e0b9f9ffe9", "question": "What is a sphygmomanometer used to measure?", "answer": "Blood pressure", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cdc02e347d002c297e4e4", "question": "What is the capital of Belgium?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a78", "question": "What William Faulkner novel presented its plot from four different points of view?", "answer": "The Sound and the Fury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5901d9c4709c1c34536e6eac", "question": "In the 2008 movie \"Step Brothers\", what is the name of Huff and Doback's entertainment company?", "answer": "Prestige Worldwide", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe3ee638b5801b8f54a7fb7", "question": "Which was the last major offensive operation undertaken by elite German paratroopers in World War II?", "answer": "Attack against Crete", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91a", "question": "What animal always gives birth to same sex twins?", "answer": "Armadillo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397dd", "question": "Which Hollywood Actor was born Issur Danielovitch in 1918?", "answer": "Kirk Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cacb", "question": "What is the name of the cartilage tissue which prevents food going down the wrong way?", "answer": "Epiglottis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3f3", "question": "What city is the Lighthouse of Alexandria located in?", "answer": "Pharos", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392cd", "question": "What 2001 thriller starred Halle Berry, John Travolta, and Hugh Jackman?", "answer": "Swordfish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f1", "question": "What year did Volkswagen debut the Golf?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3a", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Mrs. Rachel Lynde Is Surprised\"?", "answer": "Anne of Green Gables", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7cbcc877e98cb97778a1f", "question": "Thimphu is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d5", "question": "Which meteorological phenomena means \"a curl of hair\" in Latin?", "answer": "Cirrus clouds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbff36ce05a3942286f07", "question": "Which two popular actors starred in the lead roles in the film \"Rounders\"?", "answer": "Matt Damon and Edward Norton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0f", "question": "What was Wayne Gretzky's jersey number during his professional hockey career?", "answer": "99", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c55", "question": "What historical event is central to the novel \u201cA Tale of Two Cities\u201d?", "answer": "The French Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c8", "question": "Which US state has the least rainfall?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b3233efbf195a31e15d73a0", "question": "What does a \"kymograph\" measure?", "answer": "Oscillations", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e80", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The Short-Timers\" set?", "answer": "Vietnam War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b296", "question": "Washington's famous crossing of the Delaware was en route to what Revolutionary War battle?", "answer": "The Battle of Trenton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97b", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Kuvendi?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a80", "question": "In the Foreigner song \"Hot Blooded\", the singer has a temperature of how many degrees?", "answer": "103", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590679b5ff9c0647b50a8051", "question": "On January 1, 2016, which Canadian province became the first one to allow the testing of self-driving vehicles on public roads?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b4", "question": "Maria Sklodowska became famous under what name?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c428", "question": "Where in the body will you find your aqueous humour?", "answer": "Eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4e", "question": "The anniversary of the death of what magician is recognized as National Magic Day in the US?", "answer": "Harry Houdini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078b270eee65b76b9f2663", "question": "What was the original name for battle tanks?", "answer": "Landships (The name \"tank\" was due to the secrecy about its development project, which was leaked as research into water tanks.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab1a", "question": "What European country is the Arch of Hadrian located in?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b6", "question": "Who played Steve Urkel in the TV show \"Family Matters\"?", "answer": "Jaleel White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c4a6fbde8045e484669f", "question": "Which small African mammal keeps a watch-duty rotation throughout the day?", "answer": "Meerkat -- One, called the sentry, will keep a watch for predators by standing on its hind legs.  They rotate who is on watch.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d9382596a59cbdfbd3c1", "question": "After which battle did France officially enter the American Revolutionary War?", "answer": "Saratoga", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac24", "question": "Which country borders Suriname to the south?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a955961d1b4d384d5d678", "question": "Which fruit is affected by a grey type of fungus known commonly as Noble Rot?", "answer": "Grapes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338928", "question": "Which rock group charted \"Land of Confusion\" in 1986?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91b", "question": "What does the abbreviation \"AT&T\" stand for?", "answer": "American Telephone and Telegraph Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe528ec1bf59ab7d2e380ff", "question": "What classic school pet is considered a delicacy in Peru?", "answer": "Guinea pig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bd9cd96d05b23b28165e", "question": "Who was the only British Pope ever?", "answer": "Pope Adrian IV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bff5", "question": "What is biltong?", "answer": "Dried meat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bccd", "question": "What was the MK2 \"Pineapple\"?", "answer": "A hand grenade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21c", "question": "Traditional Scottish Highland Games feature which event where competitors throw a tapered 19 foot and 6 inch long log?", "answer": "Caber Toss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b688", "question": "What was the real last name of American folk hero Johnny Appleseed?", "answer": "Chapman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b321", "question": "Who was the last Nascar driver to serve jail time for running moonshine?", "answer": "Buddy Arrington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2132b31a458464a93c44e", "question": "The red food-coloring carmine is extracted from which source?", "answer": "Crushed beetles called cochineal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdc7eec223966ae8f88f8", "question": "Who plays Marty Byrde in the TV drama series \"Ozark?\"", "answer": "Jason Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601370cb1381754895396385", "question": "The Blondie song \"Call Me\" is featured in what movie?", "answer": "\"American Gigolo\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d17", "question": "What newspaper editor wrote the headline \"Spider-Man: Threat or Menace\"?", "answer": "J. Jonah Jameson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db7", "question": "In what movie does Walter Brennan annoy people with the question \"Was you ever bit by a dead bee\"?", "answer": "To Have and Have Not", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7a", "question": "What word describes a cut of steak containing both the T-\u00adbone and the tenderloin?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339518", "question": "What movie earned John Wayne his first Academy Award?", "answer": "True Grit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae2e", "question": "Who is widely credited for sewing the first American flag?", "answer": "Betsy Ross", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac19", "question": "When did the Comoros gain its independence from France?", "answer": "July 6, 1975", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339370", "question": "What movie won the Oscar for Best Visual Effects in 1978?", "answer": "Superman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c636", "question": "Which two features are longer on a hare than a rabbit?", "answer": "Legs and Ears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a041", "question": "Kevin Spacey plays Francis Underwood in what Netflix original series?", "answer": "House of Cards", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf3b", "question": "What drink is a mixture of brandy, egg yolks and sugar?", "answer": "Advocaat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58be2d228faf425cf37add7b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Oregon?", "answer": "Salem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b906", "question": "What was the first NBA team named after a car part?", "answer": "The Detroit Pistons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc0f8ec223966ae8f8862", "question": "Why were the Boston Red Sox said to be \"cursed\" between 1918 and 2004?", "answer": "For trading Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f4d", "question": "An episode of what sitcom spawned the phrase \"jumped the shark\"?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955a", "question": "What did the Wicked Witch of the West spell out with her broomstick in the sky in the 1939 film \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "Surrender Dorothy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b12d", "question": "What pacific atoll was the site of nuclear tests between 1946 and 1958?", "answer": "The Bikini Atoll", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339576", "question": "What Christmas single has the biggest sales of all time?", "answer": "White Christmas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990af40b72eedf883a8c705", "question": "What is Chopin's \"Piano Sonata No. 2\" also known as?", "answer": "The Funeral March", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a25f0d26682715b82711cda", "question": "What does the saying \"Requiescat in pace\" abbreviate to?", "answer": "RIP", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d60", "question": "Who is often considered the first to become a billionaire writing books?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc13", "question": "What year did designer Manolo Blahnik open his first namesakes store in Hong Kong?", "answer": "1991", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c2", "question": "What river defines the border between Texas and Mexico?", "answer": "Rio Grande River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f9", "question": "What is the second smallest country in the world?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fec8be1ec223966ae8f8844", "question": "Which television series revolves around a concierge doctor making house calls in the Hamptons?", "answer": "\"Royal Pains\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f6", "question": "Who put Humpty Dumpty together again in the traditional nursery rhyme?", "answer": "No one", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a5", "question": "Which penguin sex is larger?", "answer": "Males", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8f8f701dd7bf43be5e84a", "question": "What man did Billy Jean King beat in the so-called \"Battle of the Sexes\"", "answer": "Bobby Riggs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ce", "question": "What European art museum has a glass pyramid in its courtyard?", "answer": "The Louvre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15c", "question": "Who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1979?", "answer": "Mother Teresa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a113", "question": "What is the address of The Munsters?", "answer": "1313 Mockingbird Lane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be09", "question": "What NFL team replaced its AFL-era horse logo with a bolt of lightning?", "answer": "The San Diego Chargers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67a", "question": "What animal builds dams across streams?", "answer": "The beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c208", "question": "What year was the UK an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1908", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7bfd32b316f4693fb6795", "question": "The Christmas song \"O Come, O Come, Emmanuel\" was originally written in what language?", "answer": "Latin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1db", "question": "In the 1954 film \"A Star Is Born\" who played the leading man?", "answer": "James Mason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c9f78cb4e2c7fbd389674a", "question": "What popular French apple brandy is made by distilling cider made from selected apples?", "answer": "Calvados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c47d", "question": "What is the Gulf Stream?", "answer": "Warm ocean current in the Atlantic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f4", "question": "What was Maxwell Smart\u2019s agent number on \u201cGet Smart\u201d?", "answer": "86", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3c2194f032c0db195b47e", "question": "Where did the Battle of Bunker Hill take place?", "answer": "Although Bunker Hill was the main objective of the colonists and British military, most of the fighting occurred on Breed's Hill.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b04", "question": "Which goddess started the Trojan War?", "answer": "Eris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59774274284458f1d7854420", "question": "What was the second major television series starring Andy Griffith", "answer": "Matlock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b5", "question": "What was the birth name of sharpshooter Annie Oakley?", "answer": "Phoebe Ann Mosey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5de655d2f89b9ec3da2d335b", "question": "What belt driven engine accessory pressurizes the intake air in an automobile engine?", "answer": "Supercharger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4fa", "question": "What is the only metal that is liquid at room temperature?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd57", "question": "The Pritzker Prize is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Architecture", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb2087e83c707845b2110", "question": "A group of lizards is called what?", "answer": "A lounge", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7e", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The Last of the Mohicans\" set?", "answer": "Seven Years' War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b40", "question": "How many episodes of \"The Bob Newhart Show\" were made?", "answer": "142", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51ac9ff04d658268c9309", "question": "Which goddess helped guide Odysseus back home?", "answer": "Athena helped guide Odysseus back to Ithaca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c676", "question": "What is the largest member of the deer family living in the US?", "answer": "The moose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e5f11e3d274615ecf51453c", "question": "\"Oscitation\", is the medical term for what?", "answer": "Yawning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b984", "question": "Which small guitar associated with George Formby was patented in Hawaii in 1917?", "answer": "Ukulele", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b683", "question": "What is dentophobia a common fear of?", "answer": "Dentists", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bc25d96d05b23b281653", "question": "\"An eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth\" is a well-known phrase from what collection of 282 laws?", "answer": "The Code of Hammurabi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f6f03a9e54d890926f6cd", "question": "What country is home to the world's most rapidly-constructed skyscraper?", "answer": "China -- Broad Sustainable Building company built a 57-story building called Mini Sky City in 19 days using prefab components.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea9", "question": "What is Takeru Kobayashi famous for?", "answer": "Competitive eating", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7d00c877e98cb97778a5a", "question": "What U.S. state is closest to Africa?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eaf1cf83302ff91e46490", "question": "What city was nicknamed \"The Paris of the West\"?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8a", "question": "How long did Pope John Paul I serve?", "answer": "33 days", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7bee4877e98cb97778964", "question": "What is the most populated country in Africa?", "answer": "Nigeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2a", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Lagaan\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b159", "question": "How did Princess Diana die in 1997?", "answer": "Car accident", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff13fffb0ee8c595b6d3992", "question": "Military leader Napoleon also dabbled in writing what genre of book?", "answer": "Romance", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59cdb37765ff7d326b622a7f", "question": "\"From a Distance\" was a hit in the early 1990s for which singer?", "answer": "Bette Midler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934f", "question": "What famous ex-boyfriend of Jennifer Aniston once guest-starred on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ffa", "question": "Which mythological creature is half eagle, half lion?", "answer": "Griffin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ae85fc14007905755f79e8c", "question": "What is the largest river delta in the world?", "answer": "The Ganges-Brahmaputra Delta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb611a5dad637d903c882d", "question": "What is the Golden Gate Bridge named after?", "answer": "Golden Gate was named after the narrow, 300-foot-deep Golden Gate Strait which flows underneath it.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e4", "question": "Where did two lanterns historically hang on the night of April 18, 1775?", "answer": "Boston's Old North Church", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abdb", "question": "What is Canberra's Telstra Tower also known as?", "answer": "Black Mountain Tower", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5afad941430e050a5df0d114", "question": "According to most sources, where is the world\u2019s tallest unclimbed unclimable mountain?", "answer": "Bhutan/China", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a096", "question": "Which film features the line, \"I could have been a contender\"?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ec3f08d98002fdd633b9", "question": "What character, created by A. A. Milne, loves watercress?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d54", "question": "What famous double negative is the first line in Pink Floyd's \"Another Brick in the Wall (Part II)\"?", "answer": "We don't need no education", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338904", "question": "What form of theater was the subject of many of Degas' paintings?", "answer": "Ballet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393fe", "question": "What fictional type of dinosaur was Dino, the family pet on \"The Flinstones\"?", "answer": "Snorkasaurus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9b0", "question": "What university is home to the Fighting Irish?", "answer": "University of Notre Dame", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d7af2596a59cbdfbd3b9", "question": "Who is credited with the legend of the Lost City of Atlantis?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a107", "question": "\"Eyes Wide Shut\" was the last film of which director?", "answer": "Stanley Kubrick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e54", "question": "What European city do Ethan Hawke and Julie Delpy wander in the movie \"Before Sunrise\"?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad29", "question": "What US Midwestern city garnered the nickname Porkopolis in 19th century?", "answer": "Cincinnati", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a4", "question": "What is the name of the old gray donkey in Winnie-the-Pooh?", "answer": "Eeyore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b699", "question": "What is a \"crotchless portafilter\"?", "answer": "A single-holed espresso machine filter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133978b", "question": "Who directed the 1971 movie \"A Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "Stanley Kubrick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f86", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in Children of a Lesser God?", "answer": "Marlee Matlin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c90a", "question": "Which continent is the natural habitat of the Ostrich?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d9", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Trans-Europe Express\"?", "answer": "Kraftwerk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d118314fea7fe947a22282", "question": "Which part of the body is dermatology concerned with?", "answer": "The skin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dee", "question": "From what language is English has said to borrow the word \"posh\"?", "answer": "Romany", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aba", "question": "For what movie did Cher win a Best Actress Oscar?", "answer": "Moonstruck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338887", "question": "What is the singular of graffiti?", "answer": "Graffito", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d115da4fea7fe947a2226a", "question": "Ernest Evans became famous under what name?", "answer": "Chubby Checker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd69fa76c0f9723ab15cb2d", "question": "What was Martin Luther King, Jr.'s birth name?", "answer": "Michael", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c0", "question": "In The Simpsons, who is Cletus, the slack-jawed yokel married to?", "answer": "Brandine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067ccaff9c0647b50a806f", "question": "Which pop singer\u2019s reissued Christmas album was subtitled \"Snow Queen Edition\"?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b530e662d71a53650ff6", "question": "Writing for a newspaper, what did Edgar Allan Poe encourage his readers to do?", "answer": "Send him encoded messages.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51ce3ff04d658268c931e", "question": "Who invented the rubber band?", "answer": "In 1845, Stephen Perry, of the rubber manufacturing company Messers Perry and Co., invented the rubber band.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6f", "question": "Edam cheese comes from what country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339efe", "question": "What famous horse belonged to The Lone Ranger?", "answer": "Silver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e5f11add274615ecf51453a", "question": "In what country was the worlds first ice hotel built?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3c", "question": "Who founded the John Birch Society?", "answer": "Robert Welch", "category": "history"}]